purchasingpower.com 2019-05-19

# Privacy Policy | Purchasing Power

Purchasing Power is committed to protecting your privacy because our business is based on the trust you place in us. The information we collect is gathered to ensure secure ordering and to provide a more personalized shopping experience. 

  * What information do you collect?
  * How do I make a purchase with Purchasing Power?
  * Is my information used for any other purposes?
  * Will my information be given to any other party?
  * Why do I receive communications to participate in research?
  * How do we protect your information?
  * Who can see your account information?
  * Will I be notified on how you use my information?
  * What are cookies?
  * How do I give my feedback?
  * How can I update my account information?
  * What is your Customer Privacy Statement?

 **What information do you collect?**

  *  **IP address** \- We use your IP address to measure our site traffic and to help provide a relevant shopping experience. Your IP address is not linked to your customer information.
  *  **Browser type** \- Your browser type is captured to optimize our website to be compatible with the latest technologies.
  *  **Website activity** \- We track the pages you visit to provide a more personalized and relevant shopping experience.

Back to Top

**How do I make a purchase with Purchasing Power?**  
Generally, in order to purchase our products, you must be employed by a company or belong to an organization with whom we have a contractual agreement to offer products for purchase pursuant to a payroll deduction schedule. Your name, delivery address and verification of employment information are required to complete the purchase, if you intend to utilize payroll deduction as your purchase option.

Back to Top

 **Is my information used for any other purposes?**  
We require only the personal information that is needed for safely processing your online order and for contacting you about your transactions. It is used exclusively for that purpose, as described in this policy. If you become a Purchasing Power customer, you may receive mailings from your account information which may be analyzed as part of our standard business practices.

Back to Top

 **Will my information be given to any other party?**  
Information collected on this website will only be used for the purpose of processing your order and transacting business with you. Your personal information including email address, may be shared with your sponsoring organization or employer under some circumstances. Under no circumstances will your information be shared with any unaffiliated parties.

Back to Top

 **Why do I receive communications to participate in research?**  
Purchasing Power is committed to providing excellent customer experience. In order to measure how well we are doing and better understand how we can continually improve our product offering, we may contact you by phone or e-mail and solicit your participation in research. Your participation is voluntary and you may unsubscribe by updating your communication preferences.

Purchasing Power may occasionally send promotional or product information. In addition, Purchasing Power may send you updates on important information about products and services. If you do not wish to receive such e-mails, simply let us know.

Back to Top

 **How do we protect your information?**  
We employ powerful 128-bit encryption technology and Secure Socket Layers (SSL) in all areas where your personal identity is required. For your protection, this site is certified by a trusted SSL Certificate. This is your assurance that our site is authentic and that we're employing SSL security. You can check this security protection setting within your browser. To view our SSL certificate, click on the image of the closed lock or the solid key at the bottom of your browser. Our site security information will appear. For more information, contact your browser's publisher. For additional protection, your account information and order history are kept behind a firewall on separate servers. All transaction information is processed under encrypted channels. To be sure you have the most protection available, be sure to download the latest version of today's most popular browsers, Microsoft Internet Explorer and Firefox. In addition, access to your personal information is restricted within our company to provide maximum security.

Back to Top

 **Who can see your account information?**  
Only authorized sales, customer service and accounting personnel are permitted access to your account information. Once you have registered with us, we will never ask you for your username, password, or password retrieval information.  Purchasing Power employees who violate our privacy pledge will be subject to our normal disciplinary process. When we hire other organizations to provide support services, we will require them to conform to our privacy pledge and to allow us to audit them for compliance.

Back to Top

 **Will I be notified on how you use my information?**  
If we change how your personal information is used, we will notify you by prominently posting notice of the change to this site.

Back to Top

 **What are cookies?**  
Your browser offers cookies that store small amounts of data on your computer about your visits to our sites. Cookies assist us in tracking which of our features you like best. And when you re-visit our sites, cookies can enable us to recognize that you are a return visitor and to customize our content according to your preferences. However, cookies tell us nothing about you personally unless you choose to give us additional information.

We may use cookies to:

  * Keep count of your return visits to our website
  * Accumulate and report anonymous, aggregate, statistical information on website usage
  * Deliver content specific to your interests
  * Save your username so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit our website

Back to Top

 **How do I give my feedback?**  
Click here to contact Customer Service.

Back to Top

 **How can I update my account information?**

Login to the website and proceed to My Account > Profile Information. You can update your information online to keep your customer information complete, up-to-date, and accurate. Click here to update your information.

Back to Top

 **What is your Customer Privacy Statement?**

This Privacy Statement explains how we collect and use information of customers with whom we have an ongoing relationship.  If you are not a Purchasing Power customer, this Privacy Statement does not apply to you. Please refer to the Web Site Privacy Policy above.

  **FACTS**

| 

WHAT DOES PURCHASING POWER DO WITH YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?  
  
---|---  
  
 **Why?**

| 

Financial companies choose how they share your personal information. Federal law gives consumers the right to limit some but not all sharing. Federal law also requires us to tell you how we collect, share, and protect your personal information. Please read this notice carefully to understand what we do.  
  
  **What?**

| 

The types of personal information we collect and share depend on the product  or service you have with us. This information can include:

§  Social Security number and income

§  Account balances and payment history

§  Credit history and credit scores  
  
 **How?**

| 

All financial companies need to share customer's personal information to run their everyday business. In the section below, we list the reasons financial companies can share their customer's personal information; the reason Purchasing Power chooses to share; and whether you can limit this sharing.  
  
 **Reasons we can share your personal information**

| 

 **Does Purchasing**

 **Power share?**

| 

  **Can you limit this sharing?**  
  
---|---|---  
  
 **For our everyday business purposes-** such as to process your transactions, maintain your account(s), respond to court orders and legal investigations, or report to credit bureaus

| 

Yes

| 

No  
  
 **For our marketing purposes-**

to offer our products and services to you

| 

Yes

| 

No  
  
 **For joint marketing with other financial companies**

| 

Yes

| 

No  
  
 **For our affiliates' everyday business purposes-**

information about your creditworthiness

| 

No

| 

We don’t share  
  
 **For our affiliates to market to you**

| 

No

| 

We don’t share  
  
 **For non-affiliates to market to you**

| 

No

| 

We don’t share  
  
 **  Who we are**  
  
---  
  
 **  Who is providing this notice?**

| 

Purchasing Power  
  
 **  What we do**  
  
 **How does Purchasing Power protect my personal information?**

| 

To protect your personal information from unauthorized access and use, we use security measures that comply with federal law. These measures include computer safeguards and secured files and buildings.  
  
 **How does Purchasing Power collect my personal information?**

| 

We collect your personal information, for example, when you

§   open an account or give us your contact information

§    pay your bills or provide account information

§    pay us by check

 We also collect your personal information from others, such as credit bureaus, affiliates, or other companies.

Once you have registered with us, we will never ask you for your username, password, or password retrieval information.  
  
 **Why can't I limit all sharing?**

| 

Federal law gives you the right to limit only

§   sharing for affiliates' everyday business purposes - information about your creditworthiness

§   affiliates from using your information to market to you

§   sharing for non-affiliates to market to you

State laws and individual companies may give you additional rights to limit sharing.  
  
 **What happens when I limit sharing for an account I hold jointly with someone else?**

| 

Your choices will apply to everyone on your account.  
  
 **Definitions**  
  
 **Affiliates**

| 

Companies related by common ownership or control. They can be financial and nonfinancial companies.  
  
 **Non-affiliates-**

to offer our products and services to you

| 

Companies not related by common ownership or control. They can be financial and non-financial companies.

§   Purchasing Power does not share with non-affiliates for purposes of marketing.  
  
 **Joint marketing-**

to offer our products and services to you

| 

A formal agreement between nonaffiliated financial companies that together market financial products or services to you.

§   Our joint marketing partners include financial companies.  
  
 **  Other important information**  
  
 **California Residents Only:** Purchasing Power does not share your personal information with affiliates. Purchasing Power does not share your personal information for joint marketing with other financial companies.

 **Vermont Residents Only:** Except with the authorization or consent of the Vermont resident, Purchasing Power will not share among its affiliates information we receive from customer application materials, consumer reports and information we receive from others about Vermont residents.  
  
Back to Top
